Timothy Ryan Murphy

1545 W. Addison St., Apartment B. Chicago, IL 60613 · (312) 391-9751 · timothymu@gmail.com

PROFILE:

Excel at providing comprehensive secure network design, systems analysis, web design, and full cycle project management and system design. Hands-on experience leading all stages of the System Development Life Cycle efforts, including requirements definition, design, architecture, testing, and support. Successfully was a part of a wide range of Information Technology projects while participating in the planning, analysis, and implementation of proposed business information technology solutions designed in a professional environment.

EDUCATION:

Kaplan University Des Moines, Iowa

Master's of Science in Information Technology, GPA: 4.0/4.0 Emphasis: Decision Support Systems and Database Management

Graduation: April 2011

Governor's State University University University Parkway, Illinois

Bachelors of Art in Communications, GPA: 3.4/4.0

Emphasis: Media Design Graduation: February 2008

JOB RELATED SKILLS:

- Operating Systems: Windows 7, Windows XP, Mac OS X

- Languages: SQL, XML, CSS, HTML, and basic understanding of JavaScript and SAS
- **Software:** Microsoft SQL Server 2008 and 2014, Adobe CS4, Adobe CS5, DB2, Blue Zone, Microsoft Office Suite, and Thunderhead
- **Development:** Data Modeling, Database Design, System Design, SDLC, Project Management, Quality Assurance
- **Government Regulations:** Knowledge of health care Federal regulations and public policies, Health Care Reform changes, familiar with Medicare and Medicaid regulations, Leave of Absence policies, Health Savings Accounts, and the Affordable Care Act

JOB RELATED EXPERIENCE:

bswift – August 2019 to Present

Director

- Manage a team of 9 data managers and analysts
- Analyze, define, create, and test processes to populate and maintain client data in the bswift system
- Subject matter expert in bswift data needs including initial data conversion, ongoing data import processes, and automated audit processes using scripts to verify and maintain data integrity
- Participate in discussions with clients to define initial data conversion needs as well as ongoing data import file specifications
- Develop, test, and maintain the data mapping and import processes required for accurate and efficient ongoing service delivery
- Audit production data and modify when needed using T-SQL

- Work with the Director of Data Conversion to continuously refine and improve data import processes
- Assist ongoing service teams with data import needs as requested
- Develop and code payroll files based off of client requirements using SQL
- Develop reports and interfaces using T-SQL and other tools for client payroll needs such as closed loop payroll
- Triage payroll tickets and modify existing SQL code to meet new client requirements
- Write scripts, functions, and stored procedures to meet client payroll requirements

bswift – August 2017 to August 2019

Associate Director

- Manage a team of 6 data managers and analysts
- Analyze, define, create, and test processes to populate and maintain client data in the bswift system
- Subject matter expert in bswift data needs including initial data conversion, ongoing data import processes, and automated audit processes using scripts to verify and maintain data integrity
- Participate in discussions with clients to define initial data conversion needs as well as ongoing data import file specifications
- Develop, test, and maintain the data mapping and import processes required for accurate and efficient ongoing service delivery
- Audit production data and modify when needed using T-SQL
- Work with the Director of Data Conversion to continuously refine and improve data import processes
- Assist ongoing service teams with data import needs as requested
- Develop and code payroll files based off of client requirements using SQL
- Develop reports and interfaces using T-SQL and other tools for client payroll needs such as closed loop payroll
- Triage payroll tickets and modify existing SQL code to meet new client requirements
- Write scripts, functions, and stored procedures to meet client payroll requirements

bswift – September 2014 to August 2017

Data Manager/Payroll Developer

- Analyze, define, create, and test processes to populate and maintain client data in the bswift system
- Subject matter expert in bswift data needs including initial data conversion, ongoing data import processes, and automated audit processes using scripts to verify and maintain data integrity
- Participate in discussions with clients to define initial data conversion needs as well as ongoing data import file specifications
- Develop, test, and maintain the data mapping and import processes required for accurate and efficient ongoing service delivery
- Audit production data and modify when needed using T-SQL
- Work with the Director of Data Conversion to continuously refine and improve data import processes
- Assist ongoing service teams with data import needs as requested
- Develop and code payroll files based off of client requirements using SQL
- Develop reports and interfaces using T-SQL and other tools for client payroll needs such as closed loop payroll
- Triage payroll tickets and modify existing SQL code to meet new client requirements
- Write scripts, functions, and stored procedures to meet client payroll requirements

Implementation Analyst

- Implement client sites by participating in requirements sessions with clients, site building, site testing, and site release to the production environment
- Provide follow ups of decisions made, open items, and next steps from ongoing client meetings
- Interpret requirement artifacts in-order to build and test client sites, including benefit plan rules, permission matrix, alerts, rates, client site text and managing client library documents
- Address any requirement questions to the Implementation Manager and Leader and escalate any issues/risks when identified
- Developed clear test plans for online client acceptance testing and end to end file processing
- Brand client sites using CSS, HTML, and basic JavaScript
- Import test demographic data and rates into bswift's system using Import 2.0 functionality
- Analyze and audit client data to verify accuracy between the client's system and bswift
- Assist the Implementation Manager in debugging issues and implementing resolutions
- Produce reports providing summary and analysis for audits using Excel functionality for data conversion audits (vlookups, concatenating data, pivot tables, arithmetic formulas, counting, and converting data)
- Write basic SQL queries using Microsoft SQL Server 2008 in-order to improve data retrieval efficiency
- Assist the Implementation Leader and Manager with the transition to the ongoing process to ensure a successful knowledge and functionality handoff
- Perform a wide variety of tasks and projects in a team-oriented environment

Aon Hewitt - June 2013 to April 2014

Systems Analyst

- Implement the Software Development Life Cycle principles and concepts
- Deliver clear analysis, test plans, and standard operating procedures which accurately reflect the technical capacities of the system
- Address the requirements of the client through comprehensive analysis artifacts while leading weekly team meetings for team members in India
- Responsible for coordinating and coaching other team members on system configuration and test execution of the technology platform
- Help with the extension and enhancement of current technology services for clients who are already live in the production database
- Design, update, and deliver unit, integration, regression, and acceptance test plans
- Assist with the deployment and migration of new system updates into the production environment
- Coach team members on defect management, debugging, reporting, and system specifications
- Review configuration and test plan documentation and evaluate the results of test execution results
- Coordinate the work, monitor task completion, and communicate team scheduling and status of Setup Configuration Specialists to the Lead System Analyst
- Contribute to data mapping, new population conversion requirements, and finding the resolution to any open issues that might occur
- Use SQL to query, update, and manage relational databases
- Triage cross-client Personalized Communication Statement issues through the software Thunderhead and XML

- Use best practices and methodologies for system testing and quality assurance
- Implement the Software Development Life Cycle principles and concepts
- Interpret conditional statements and analyze data by generating reports
- Apply relational database concepts
- Use SQL to query, update, and manage relational databases
- Write defense queries in-order to discover database and system issues
- Assist in troubleshooting system defects and system errors
- Interpret client requirements and implement provisions to meet system functionality
- Work with JCL and SAS code
- Help design and implement a new database for the Health and Welfare department
- Assist in the customization of code for various participant communication statements using Thunderhead software
- Analyze conversion error data reports to identify data verses system issues
- Assist in various advanced cross-client projects that were new to the Health and Welfare database
- Able to communicate ideas in a both technical and user friendly language